Count Cruhteo?
クルーテオ伯爵？
Yes. His eldest son inherited the title.
はい　継承されたご嫡男です
Klancain...
クランカインか
He is reputed to be extremely loyal to the emperor.
皇帝に対する忠誠心は極めて厚いと聞いております
By now the knights are split clean into those on my side and those on the emperor's.
未だこちらに靡かぬ者たちは　いわば皇帝派だ
If we can convince him to join us,
perhaps the others will rethink their allegiance.
彼をこちらの陣営に引き入れる事ができれば
一気に裏返る可能性もある
I agree.
はい
It will depend on whether or not he is truly trustworthy.
だが　果たして信用に足る相手か否か
Deucalion, launch!
デューカリオン発進
All ahead, dead slow!
両舷前進最微速
これより大気圏を脱し　サテライトベルトへ向かう
We will leave the Earth's atmosphere and ascend to the satellite belt.
Our destination is Parnassos Base!
集結地点は　パルナッソス基地
kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with what the sea of reason would give
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kouka shita kotoba uso kimagure
Words, lies, and whim down from orbit
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
soul art
Soul art
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
We play a song now
aizu wo ringu ni tsunagu
and connect the signs to a ring
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
toubounin no hajirai on
The sound of shy fugitives
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou drive carryon iji na tire
Carry on imagining, don't give up
gokai aru doa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
We're running out of false doors
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
tokei daita hito to tenshi
Men and angels embrace the passage of time
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni aku doorutachi
They are dolls who gave up on eternity,
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against this recurring fever
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
攻撃目標は敵月面基地
The target of the attack is the enemy moon base.
アセイラム姫がいる敵の本丸だ
Princess Asseylum is in their stronghold.
As there is a Landing Castle in close proximity to the moon base
そして　近接する宙域にある揚陸城は
月面基地が攻撃を受けた際
which would likely shelter her in the event of an attack,
アセイラム姫の避難先として使われる可能性も考えられるため
both fortifications will need
to be attacked simultaneously.
この二つの拠点に同時に攻撃をかける必要がある
Consequently, our forces will be split for this operation.
よって　本作戦においては戦力を二つに分け
Breton Platoon and the Deucalion
will attack the Landing Castle at 2200 UTC.
ブルトン中隊並びにデューカリオンは　地球標準時2200を期し
揚陸城に攻撃を開始
月面基地の敵戦力が　揚陸城の防衛に割かれたことが確認できた後
Once we have confirmation that the moon base
has sent out its garrison to defend the Landing Castle,
Trakehner Platoon will approach under cover
of the numerous asteroids in the area and strike.
トラケナー中隊は　周囲に点在する大型岩石を利用
その背後に隠れつつ　敵基地へ接近　強襲をかける
This mission is designated Operation Lunar Gate.
以後　作戦名をオペレーション・ルナゲートと呼称する
申し訳ありません　姫様
Forgive me, Your Highness.
私が至らなかったばかりに
I should have been more vigilant.
No.
いいえ　責任を負うべきは私です
It is I who must shoulder the blame.
事のすべては　私から始まったこと
None of this would have happened without my actions.
そんな　姫様
But, Your Highness...
そうよ
Exactly.
あなたがいなければ…
If you weren't around, if you'd stayed unconscious,
あなたがあのまま眠っていれば　全てはうまく納まっていた
then I would have had everything under control.
泣く者なんかいなかったのに
Nobody wept for you,
あの人も心を乱されずに済んだのに
and he would not be as confused as he is now.
心から想っているのですね　スレインのことを
You care deeply for Slaine, don't you?
あなたは　あなたはどうなの
And you? What about you?
誰のことを想っているの
Who do you care for?
私が想いを捧げるのは　ヴァースという星とそこに住む人々
I am devoted to the world of Vers and its people.
そう教えられ　生きてきました
That is what I was taught, and how I lived.
可哀想な人
I pity you.
本艦はブルトン中隊とともに　揚陸城を攻撃
We will attack the Landing Castle together with Breton Platoon.
月面基地の攻撃と合わせ
We will form one half of the operation,
the other being the attack on the moon base.
二正面作戦の一端を担う
司令部からデューカリオンに与えられた任務は以上です
This is the mission we've been given by HQ.
A two-pronged operation, huh?
二正面作戦って…
要は敵の分散を誘っているだけの話だ
So we're basically only there to divide their forces.
またこの船を囮にしてな
Sounds to me like we're just bait.
しかし　その役割に無為に甘んじるつもりは毛頭ありません
However, I have no intention of quietly accepting that role.
皆　無駄に命を投げ出すことなく
I want everyone present to come back alive so that we can all celebrate on Earth.
再び地球に戻るまで　最善を尽くしてください
Don't be reckless.
Dismissed.
以上
各位　所定の配置につけ
All hands, to your stations.
艦長
Captain?
来るだろうと思っていました
I had a feeling you'd want to talk to me.
こちらもお話があります
I would like to speak with you too.
I apologize for the delay.
お待たせしました
此度は我が父ザーツバルムへの弔問のため
You've come a very long way to offer your condolences over the death of my father.
わざわざおいでいただいたとか
We are a great distance from Vers.
何分　ヴァースからは遠い道程
トロイヤード卿のご継承のお喜びも含め　すっかり遅れてしまいまして
My condolences for your father and my congratulations for your succession are long overdue.
こちらこそ
I fear I must apologize for failing to congratulate you on your own succession, Count Cruhteo.
クルーテオ卿の襲爵のお祝いを申し上げぬまま　失礼を
Please, call me Klancain.
I am still unaccustomed to my father's title.
クランカインで結構です　まだどうも馴れず
では　そのように
Very well.
Princess Asseylum was looking forward to seeing you again after so long, but...
アセイラム姫様も
クランカイン卿に久々にお会いできることを楽しみにしておりましたが
ご体調を崩されているとか
I was given to understand
that she is not in good health.
さほどのこともないようですが　大事を取りまして
It's nothing grave, but she should be given time to recuperate.
お父上には大変お世話になりました
I am deeply indebted to your father.
ご苦労されたのでは？
Was he not hard on you?
厳格すぎるほどに厳格な人でありましたから
He was a painfully austere man.
たくさんの事を学ばせていただきました
He taught me many valuable things.
私がいまあるのもお父上のおかげと思っています
I doubt that I would be standing here right now were it not for him.
タルシスを見ました
I saw the Tharsis.
今はトロイヤード卿のお役に立てているようで　何よりです
I am glad that it has been of use to you.
こちらに向かう途中　聞きました
Also, I heard en route that you had proclaimed your intention to found a new kingdom here.
地球圏に王国を築かれるという宣言をされたとか
それがアセイラム姫様の望みでしたから
It was Princess Asseylum's wish.
皇帝陛下にとってもですか
Was it also His Imperial Majesty's?
ご体調が思わしくないとか
As I understand, his health is failing.
最新の医療機器と最高の医療スタッフで対応しています
He has the best doctors,
equipped with the best medical technology.
ご心配には及びません
There is no need to worry about him.
それはよかった
I am glad to hear that.
アセイラム姫様のご希望が叶えば
If we should see Princess Asseylum's wishes come to fruition,
陛下もさぞやお喜びになることでしょう
I am sure His Majesty would be overjoyed as well.
そうであればいいですね
One would hope so.
クランカイン卿にもお力添えいただければ　大変心強いのですが
If you were to assist us in our struggles, Lord Klancain,
it would bolster morale a great deal.
期待しています
I am looking forward...
to seeing how your new kingdom will affect the future of Vers.
新たな王国がヴァースの未来を変えることを
不自然な動きをしている岩石群を調べたところ
We noticed a number of asteroids behaving erratically.
密度の異なる物体が背後に
It would appear objects of different density are in their shadow.
カモフラージュか
Camouflage, huh?
ステイギス隊は
How is the Stygis Platoon?
出撃の準備はできております
Ready for launch.
クランカイン伯爵を安全な場所へ
See Count Klancain to a safe location.
敵軍隊　あと7分で射程距離まで接近します
Enemy force will be in range in seven minutes.
応戦しつつ　前線を徐々に下げ
Start pulling back once we engage,
and draw the enemy out with you.
敵勢力を月面基地から遠ざけます
全艦戦闘配置
All personnel to combat stations.
これより　発進シークエンスへ移行する
Beginning launch sequence.
フライホイール　接続
Flywheel connected.
カタパルトアーム　回転開始
Catapult arm rotating.
ハッチ開放
Opening hatch.
クライスデール小隊　発進位置
Clydesdale Platoon to launch point.
ラジャー　クライスデールリーダーより各機
Roger.
Clydesdale Leader to all units.
Go to launch point.
発進位置へ
アンカーエンゲージ　カタパルトアーム　回転正常
Anchors engaged.
Catapult arm rotation within parameters.
加速開始
Beginning acceleration.
Twenty seconds until launch rotation.
発進可能まで20秒
クライスデールリーダー　クリアード・フォー・ランチ
You're cleared for launch, Clydesdale Leader.
Roger, cleared for launch.
ラジャー　クリアード・フォー・ランチ
全機発進
All units go.
Blast off!
ブラストオフ
続いてマスタング小隊　発進準備
Now, Mustang Platoon.
Prepare for launch.
ブルトン中隊並びにデューカリオンは　予定通り攻撃を開始
Breton Platoon and the Deucalion
will commence their attack as planned.
Roger.
了解　こちらも行くぞ
Let's go.
攻撃開始
Attack!
天秤座の方角に　敵機影多数
Multiple enemy contacts coming in from Libra.
カタフラクトです
They're Cataphracts!
迎撃しろ
Intercept them.
始まった
It's begun.
Yeah.
やっぱり　敵の防御は堅い
The enemy's defenses are pretty tough.
苦戦することは最初から目に見えていた
It was obvious from the start that this'd be an uphill battle.
それでも　この作戦を強行する必要があったのは
The reason we had to go ahead with this mission
was because HQ has an even bigger goal in mind.
司令部にはもっと重要なミッションがあったからだ
艦長がおかしいと感じていたとおり
The Captain was right to be suspicious.
総攻撃の合間を縫って　アサルト部隊を隠密裏に潜入させる
That assault team is using our offensive as cover for an infiltration.
破壊工作？
For sabotage?
いや　それなら秘密にする必要はない
No. There'd be no need to infiltrate secretly for that.
目的はやはり
I would suspect their objective...
アセイラム姫の暗殺
is to assassinate Princess Asseylum.
Bastard!
この…
ファイア
Fire.
次
Next.
最接近まで90秒
They'll be closest to us in ninety seconds.
了解　じゃあ　予定通りに
Roger. Move according to plan, then.
韻子
Inko.
元々一人で来る気だった
I was supposed to do this alone.
It's going to get dangerous from here on.
ここから先は危険だ　だから…
So—
Seriously, this again? Gimme a break.
ああ　やだやだ　またそういうの
今までやってきたことを認めて　艦長が私をサポートにつけたんだから
The captain assigned me to support you
out of recognition for my accomplishments.
伊奈帆や皆と一緒に　戦ってきたこと
I've been fighting right beside you
and the others all this time, after all.
ごめん　韻子
Sorry, Inko.
よし　行こう
Okay. Let's do this.
もう大丈夫　このあたりから降下する
This is close enough.
I'll make my descent from here.
It's dangerous. You're still at high altitude.
危険よ　まだ高度が高い
敵機だ
Incoming!
僕を下ろせ　このままじゃ対応出来ない
Let me go! You're a sitting duck right now!
It's okay! The wind's strong!
大丈夫
風が強い　この距離なら避けられる
I can dodge at this range!
Inko!
韻子
Just a little farther!
あと少し
ユキさん
Yuki!
Leave this to me!
こっちは任せて
Thanks, Yuki.
ありがとう　ユキ姉
もう大丈夫だ　韻子
You can drop me now, Inko.
了解
Roger.
Be careful.
気をつけて
ここから分かれる
This is where we split up.
All teams, investigate your assigned routes.
各班　所定のルートを探索
Execute your missions as soon as you spot your target.
ターゲットを見つけ次第　速やかに目的を遂行すること
That's all.
以上だ
Ambush!
待ち伏せだ
潜入部隊も想定の上だ
I knew they would send an infiltration team.
敵は別のブロックにも潜入しているものと思われます
I believe this is not the only block the enemy has infiltrated.
I will dispatch the palace guard.
衛兵を向かわせています
And the princesses?
姫たちは？
Evacuating to a more secure location as we speak.
安全な区画へ避難中です
Count Troyard.
トロイヤード卿
I, Barouhcruz, have rushed to your side, swift as the wind.
バルークルス　応援に馳せ参じた
You're here?
来てくれたか　感謝する
You have my thanks.
ハークライトもそちらに向かわせる
I will send Harklight to you.
What in the world is happening?
一体　何が起こっているのです？
ここは食い止める　お前たちはターゲットを探せ
I'll keep them busy.
You guys find the target!
基地内の監視映像を取り込んで　マップの生成
Importing base security footage and generating map.
I'm using you too much, huh?
使いすぎか
I'll be all right.
大丈夫だ
潜入した部隊の位置を確認
Infiltration team located.
その向かう先に　きっとセラムさんが
And beyond them... is where Seylum will be.
行ける　このまま　敵殲滅も
We can do this.
We might even kill 'em all...
超電磁ボビンに巻かれた分子サイズの超々高張力ワイヤー
Ultra high-tension monofilament wire spooled around a superconducting electromagnetic bobbin.
There is nothing this blade cannot cut through.
この刃に切れぬものはない
周りのネズミどもは任せたぞ　ハークライト卿
I'll leave the rat extermination to you, Count Harklight.
Consider it done.
お任せを
目標発見
Target spotted!
Get behind me!
お下がりください
二人共…
Girls!
Please run, Your Highness!
お逃げください　姫様
Sir Slaine, we've lost contact with the palace guards!
スレイン様
護衛から連絡が途絶えました
What?
何？　姫たちは
And the princesses?
発着ポートに向かっていますが　敵もそちらに
They're headed for the landing port,
but so is the enemy!
Dispatching immediate reinforc—
直ちに新たな要員を
I'll go!
私が向かう
Why would you help me?
どうして　私を…
人を救うのに　理由など要りません
I need no reason to save a life.
The ego on you.
傲慢ね
救われる側の苦しみなど　知りはしないのね
You have no idea how much it can hurt to be saved.
Princess Lemrina!
レムリナ様
もういいわ　私はここに残る
Keep going.
I'll stay here.
We have to escape!
早く逃げないと
どこに逃げるの
Escape to where?
And from whom?
誰の手から
I'm certain we can find safety—
必ず救いは
私にとっては　ここが唯一の逃げ場なの
This place is my only refuge.
Go.
行って
Where is this?
ここは…
もう一度…　もう一度サーチしてくれ
Do it again.
Search again, please.
Seylum...
セラムさんは　きっと近くに
has to be nearby.
お前が来るとはな　界塚伊奈帆
I didn't expect to see you here, Kaizuka Inaho.
スレイン・トロイヤード
Slaine Troyard...
銃弾の軌跡より射点を計測
Calculate point of origin from bullet trajectory.
サーモグラフィ
Thermography.
蒸気管か
Steam pipes, huh?
セラムさんは…　アセイラム姫はどこだ
Where's Seylum—Princess Asseylum?
彼女を巻き込むな
Keep her out of this!
Out of it?
巻き込む？
She and my goal go hand in hand.
目指す目的の傍らに姫がいる　それだけの話だ
That's all there is to it!
So you're just using her?
姫を利用するのか
利用されると
Using her?
What's it to you?
困るのか
最初から　お前は敵だった
You were the enemy from the day we met!
敵でしかなければ　憎む必要はなかった
If that was all, there would be no need for hate!
Over there!
あそこだ
After him!
追え
行きましょう
Let's go.
エデルリッゾ
Eddelrittuo!
Are you all right, Eddelrittuo?
大丈夫ですか　エデルリッゾ
What about you, Your Highness?
姫様こそ
Your Highness!
姫様
セラムさん
Seylum?
伊奈帆さん
Inaho!
Seylum...
セラムさん
よかった　無事で
I'm glad...
you're okay...
Inaho!
伊奈帆さん
姫様
Your Highness!
伊奈帆さん
Inaho!
伊奈帆さん…
Ina...
アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシア姫殿下　確認
Princess Asseylum Vers Allusia, confirmed.
Inaho?
伊奈帆さん？
思考停止　バックアッププログラム　適用
Thought processes offline.
Running backup program.
What's the matter, Inaho?
どうしたのです？　伊奈帆さん
界塚伊奈帆の思考　認識及び発話機能を一時的に代替する
Temporarily assuming control of Kaizuka Inaho's thoughts, cognizance, and speech capabilities.
あなたは
Who are you?
この少年はアセイラム姫殿下を自己とは別の個体と認識しながらも
This boy, despite recognizing the individual identity of "Princess Asseylum,"
also misidentifies you as part of himself.
自己の一部と誤認している
自己の一部？
Part of himself?
For that reason, he put your safety on maximum priority and acted to preserve your life.
よって最大限　姫殿下の安全を望み
保護しようと行動している
私を　助けに？
He came to save me?
その行動原理に則して　情報を提供する
In accordance with this maxim, I will provide you with the appropriate information.
F3ゲート　エアロック内通信回路から網文韻子に連絡せよ
Contact Amifumi Inko via the
communications line in the F3 gate airlock.
デューカリオンの皆さんが　こちらに来ているのですか
The people of the Deucalion are coming here?
Let us go, Your Highness.
行きましょう　姫様
そのエアロックの場所なら　分かります
I know where that airlock is.
でも　伊奈帆さんをこのままには
But we can't leave Inaho—
心配には及ばない
There is no cause for concern.
In four hundred and twenty seconds, my comrades will arrive.
420秒後　仲間が救出に来る
だったら　姫様　なおさら　早く
Which is exactly why we need to leave, Your Highness!
There's no telling if his
comrades will be on our side!
その仲間が味方かどうかは分かりません
Please tell him: "Thank you,
from the bottom of my heart."
お伝え下さい　心より感謝していますと
コマンド　確認
Command acknowledged.
それと…
And...
Tell him:
私も…
私もあなたのことを…
"I also think of you as part of myself."
自分の一部のように思っています
We need to leave.
行きましょう
Hold on.
待って　もう一つ
I have one more...
request.
お願いがあります
こちらです
It's this way!
お待ち下さい　今　通信設備を
Just one minute. I'll get the comms equipment on—
Princess Asseylum, is it?
アセイラム姫ですね
お覚悟を
Say your prayers.
Are you unharmed, Princess Asseylum?
お怪我は？　アセイラム姫殿下
あなたは…
You're...
Klancain?
クランカイン？
父の叙勲式以来ですね
We last met at my father's commendation ceremony.
I am honored that you remember me.
光栄です　覚えていてくださって
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikoko&Archer  翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx  时间轴:Foyzi  压制:河蟹
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
叫びはまだ遠くて
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
この宙の果てまで
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
創造を信じて
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life